Okay, so let's discuss some agile terms
now when it comes to scope management.
Now, one of the terms I
want to talk about is this one
called the product backlog,
which we've mentioned before.
But remember, a product backlog is basically
a prioritized list of user stories.
All right, now, just as a review,
right, so we have a separate video on the
Agile Life Cycle, and we mentioned product
backlog a couple of times, but just as a
simple review, Remember, at the beginning
of a release, the product owner and the
Agile team and the team facilitator, they
work with the customer
to get requirements.
Those requirements are known as user
stories.
Now, the product owner is going to
prioritize those user stories.
And a prioritized list of user stories
then is known as the product backlog.
We're going to get as many user stories as
we can.
with the understanding that that can
change.
And with the understanding also that the
priorities can change.
Because remember, Agile allows for change.
The whole principle of Agile is we're
going to deliver high value items based on
also, you know, a changing business
environment.
And so that's why we are prioritizing
these user stories.
And that prioritized list of user stories
is known as a product backlog.
Now, for each sprint then or each
iteration, right, the team and the product
owner, to work together,
right, to select the highest
priority backlog items to
implement in the sprint.
And then for that
particular sprint or iteration,
right, they're going to
create a sprint backlog.
So this is what we're going to deliver in
the sprint and this is a prioritized list
of user stories for this particular
sprint.
Again, remember, you're
constantly delivering
high value items to your customer, right?
Every couple of weeks,
every sprint, you're going
to be delivering high
value items to the customer.
High value meaning high priority.
And that's why we're prioritizing these
user stories.
So, during each sprint then, the Agile
team is going to come up with a relative
estimating, and then some of the more
detailed estimating.
They're going to break the user stories
down to individual activities,
individual tasks, and that's what they're
going to deliver during the sprint.
And of course, because
it's agile, it's subject
to change, New user stories can come in.
New user stories can be identified based
on, you know, changes to the external or
internal environment or just new user
stories have been discovered.
There might be a regulatory change,
for example.
And so now there might be some other high
priority items that
need to be implemented.
And so that now gets put into the backlog.
Everything gets reprioritized throughout,
and basically throughout the release,
throughout the project.
And reprioritization, then, is known as
Backlog Grooming.
Now, that's kind of one of the general
procedures, right?
One of the general processes you need to
know regarding Agile.
Let's talk about user stories now.
A user story has to fit a certain
template.
User story basically essentially has to
look like this.
So it always has to
have a role, always has
to have functionality
and a business benefit.
So the template, if you like, for a user
story is, as a role I want this
functionality so that there's a business
benefit.
So almost you can think of this as,
well, you can fit this on a flashcard.
And that's really the whole principle
behind the user stories.
Just think of a product backlog as a whole
list of electronic flashcards.
So it's a very simple example then.
We've got an example here.
As a call center analyst, I
want to search clients by
first and last name so I can
look at their records quicker.
So that is an example of a use story.
So as a call center analyst, and that's a
role, I want to search clients by first
and last name, that's
the functionality I want,
so that I can look up
their records quicker.
That's a business benefit I'm going to
get.
So every user story then has to be down to
this level.
And then from there, now we can,
or rather the team, can now break those
down into to individual
tasks, determine how long the
tasks are going to take,
and implement those tasks.
Now, two other very important agile terms
you should be aware of.
Definition of done and definition of
ready.
Let's talk about definition of done.
Now, in the agile world, there is no such
thing as percentage of work complete.
It's either the work is complete or it's
not complete.
So, for example, in a predictive
environment, right, you often walk around
asking your team members or
asking team leads, what's the
percentage complete on this and
the percentage complete on that.
You know, and they give you all that
information and say, oh, we're 50%
complete on this activity,
we're 80% complete
here, 90% complete
there and so and so forth.
In the agile world, that does not fly.
Either the work is complete or it's not
complete.
Simple as that.
Either it's 0% complete, or it's 100%
complete.
If the work is 99% complete, then it means
it's 0% complete.
So it's either 0% or it's 100%.
There's no grey area in between.
Now, what do we mean by?
Complete.
That's where the definition of done comes
in.
So during release planning, the product
owner, Agile team, team facilitator,
right, they get together
and then they determine,
what does it mean for
this work to be complete.
That is our definition of done, you
know, for this project, for this release.
It's a criteria to determine whether or
not the work is complete.
If it does not meet that criteria,
then it means the work is not complete.
And that's essentially what the definition
of done refers to.
Definition of ready, on the other hand, is
basically for each particular sprint now.
Right.
It's basically, does a team have all the
tools and all the information,
you know, for them to actually start the
work?
So remember, a sprint is only two to four
weeks, right?
So they don't be wasting time waiting for
information and, you know, waiting for
tools to be ready in order for them to do
the work.
So that's what the definition of Ready
refers to.
So it's a checklist to determine that all
the information is available, right,
for the team to actually start working on
that particular user story.
And as soon as we know, as soon as it
meets that definition of ready,
then immediately we can start working on
that user story.
And one of the response, that is one of
the responsibilities.
I know the team facilitator.
I mean, obviously the team is going to be
responsible for that as well, but
primarily the team facilitator,
remember, is the servant leader,
and the servant leader is making sure that
the team has all of the tools,
all of the information,
all of the data, out
everything they need to
actually perform the work.
So they are making sure then that we meet
this definition of ready, so that then
immediately then the team can start
working on the user story.
All right, so these are
just some important agile
terms that you need to
know for the PMP exam.
So make sure you understand, you know,
all these terms.
And, you know, all of these
terms, we will be covering at
various points in other sections
during this course as well.